insideweddings.com 2018-12-29

# Inside Weddings - Privacy Policy

**Last Updated on MARCH 31, 2015.  **

**INSIDE WEDDINGS: PRIVACY POLICY**

Welcome to InsideWeddings.com! Please carefully read the following Privacy Policy (“Policy”) before using InsideWeddings.com and all other mobile applications and/or other services. The Inside Weddings website, mobile application, and/or services are owned or operated by Belle Media, A California Corporation and/or its subsidiaries or affiliates (collectively, referred to herein as "we" or "us" or "our"). 

This Policy applies to all visitors/users (registered and unregistered), “Members,” and “Business Members.” We care about your privacy and wrote this Policy to help you understand the types of information we collect through InsideWeddings.com, our online services, mobile and other applications and the social networking platforms on which it is posted (each referred to herein as a "Site"), as well as how we will use, disclose and protect this information once it is collected, and how you may be able to opt out of some of our uses and disclosures of your information. By visiting this Site, you agree to the terms of this Policy as they may be amended from time to time. This Policy is incorporated into, and part of, our Terms of Use, which governs your use of the Site as a whole. Unless otherwise specified, this Policy does not apply to information that you may provide to us, or that we may obtain, other than from you through our Site, such as over the phone, by mail, or in person.

**PERSONAL INFORMATION**

While you may be able to visit and view some content on the Site without providing any Personal Information, we may collect Personal Information on or through the Site in various circumstances. Personal Information is information that can be used to identify you or contact you as an individual, as well as information attributed with such information. Personal Information includes, for example, your name; age or date of birth; postal address; email address; telephone number; wireless device address; username; photograph; gender; event dates and related information; and demographic information. We collect Personal Information via the Site in certain instances, such as when you subscribe to our publication(s); conduct a transaction on our Site; create an account on our Site; edit your online profile; sign up for our newsletters; enter sweepstakes and contests; complete surveys; or submit a comment or question to us by using a "contact us" or similar feature on the Site. On some areas of our Site, you may not be able to participate in certain activities or access content, unless you register and provide us with the requested Personal Information.

If you create an account on our Site, you are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your account password and for any activity that occurs under your account. Please immediately notify us of any unauthorized use of your password or account.

We may share your personal information (“Personal Information”) with third parties for their marketing purposes. You can elect for us not to do so by editing your preferences in your member (“Member”) account profile at [www.insideweddings.com](http://www.insideweddings.com/), or by emailing us at [membersupport@insideweddings.com](mailto:membersupport@insideweddings.com) (please include your name, mailing address, and email address). See "Your California Privacy Rights" below for additional information.

**Opt In and Opt Out**

You may have the right to opt in to or opt out of certain of our uses and disclosures of your Personal Information. For example, when you are asked to provide Personal Information on this Site, you may have the opportunity to elect to, or not to, receive promotional messages from us and/or third parties by email. You may unsubscribe from our promotional emails by editing your preferences in your account profile on the Site, or by clicking on the opt-out link within the email you receive. 

**Sharing Tool**

A "sharing" tool is made available to you by Inside Weddings. You can find the “share” tool on the Site and it may also be used in our emails and other communications to you. This tool allows Members to send information about Inside Weddings, our services and offerings, such as an article, real wedding, wedding professional/vendor (“Business Member”) listing, inspiration board, event, or image, to another person via email or social media. You acknowledge that we may store this information for marketing and tracking purposes to rate the success of the “share” feature. You may also be able to provide us with information about other people involved in your event, such as your significant other, wedding party, etc. This information will be treated in accordance with this Policy. 

**Internet-Based Call**

An Internet or mobile-based call or similar feature on the Site (e.g., Skype) enables you to contact Business Members or other third parties that are featured on the Site, such as vendors of products and services we think you may be interested in. You acknowledge that we may store this information for marketing and tracking purposes to rate the success of this feature.

**SITE MEMBERSHIP**

You may choose to register as a Member of our Site. By becoming a Member you may participate in certain activities on our Site and enjoy special benefits offered specifically to Members and/or Business Members. To become a Member or Business Member, you are required to register, and provide your name, email address, and other basic information. You will also be asked to create a username and password. You may be able to review, update or modify some areas of your Personal Information by logging in to your account. As a part of registration, you may set up a Profile describing yourself or your business. The profile will appear as a draft initially, until you mark it “published.” This profile may be publicly available as a default. You may have the ability to hide some Personal Information or make your profile private under your profile settings by marking it as a draft. Other sites and mobile applications that are part of the Site may have separate Privacy Settings.

**Social Media Accounts**

You may also register to become a Member using one of your existing social media accounts, such as Facebook or Twitter. If you become a Member using your existing social media account, your social media provider may provide us with access to any personally identifiable information on file with that social media provider and associated with your account in accordance with the provider’s terms and conditions. For example, some social networking services allow you to push content from our Site to your contacts or to pull information about your contacts so you can connect with them on or through us. You should review the privacy policies of social networking services you utilize. You can modify your privacy settings directly with those services. We reserve the right to use, transfer, assign, sell, share, and provide access to all personally identifiable information and other information about you and your computer, mobile or other device that we receive through third-party social networking services in the same ways described in this Policy.

**Inactive Accounts**

If you are a registered Member and terminate your Inside Weddings account, we will mark your account in our database as “inactive”, but will keep your information in our database. This is necessary in order to deter fraud. We will maintain information on Members who have been removed for violating our Terms of Use. We will not use your personally identifiable information for any further purpose, except as necessary to prevent fraud and assist law enforcement, or as required by law. To terminate your membership, contact us at [membersupport@insideweddings.com](mailto:membersupport@insideweddings.com). 

**Business Member Reviews**

Inside Weddings Members who are clients of participating Business Members may provide public reviews (“Review(s)”) of their work and/or services. When you submit a Review on the Site, your name and photo (if provided) will be made available as part of the Review posting. Additionally, we may make your Review public on other Inside Weddings properties or through our partners and affiliates.

Business Members will be notified via email if they have received a Review from a Member and will have the ability to respond to a Review directly on the Site. Please keep in mind that all Reviews and responses will be public and any visitor to the Site can view them.

**Business Member Directory  **

Inside Weddings provides a listing by sortable categories of participating Business Members. If your wedding professional is registered, their profile will be made available in the Directory. As specified in our Terms of Use, after Inside Weddings and the Business Member have terminated their relationship, Inside Weddings shall be entitled to retain all Reviews associated with a Business Member on the Site as well as basic directory information, including, without limitation, business name, address and telephone number.

**SITE USAGE AND TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES**

Depending on how you use and access the Site, our servers may automatically collect information about you and your computer, such as browser type, software, IP address, and other personal information to help identify you and your usage. This is typical of most websites and used for a variety of purposes, including, for example, aggregated information on demographics to assist in marketing efforts. 

We may utilize additional tracking technologies on the Site to collect detailed information about your Site visits, and may also include personal information about you. Some examples of the types of tracking technologies we may use include: cookies, web beacons, flash cookies, pixel tags, and HTML5. These technologies provide information such as: date and time of your visit; what you searched; and what you viewed. It helps us to provide you with the best user experience – personalized for you, in some instances. The technologies discussed in this section may be deployed by us or our service providers to help collect Site usage information and track traffic to, from, and around the Site. By using our Site, you acknowledge and agree to our use of these tracking technologies.

**Third Parties**

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit the Site. These companies may use information about your visits to this Site and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. These companies may employ cookies, clear GIFs and other tracking technologies to cause relevant ads to be displayed to you. We may also share aggregated Member and/or visitors information with third parties, such as our advertisers. For example, we may disclose the number of Members and/or visitors that have been exposed to, or clicked on, advertisements. Surveys on the website may also be conducted by and processed via a third party.

You may be able to opt out of such advertisements. For more information about third-party advertisers and how to prevent them from using your information, visit the Network Advertising Initiative’s consumer website at [http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/ ](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/%20)or at <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>. 

**Links to Other Websites**

The Site and our online services may contain links to third-party websites, including, but not limited to banners, widgets or advertisements. By clicking on these links, you acknowledge that you are leaving our Site and this Policy will not apply. We encourage you to read the privacy statement of third-party sites to learn about how your information is collected and shared. Your linking to a third-party page is at your own risk and we are not responsible or liable for your visitation to, and the data collection and use practices of, third-party sites.

**“Do Not Track” Disclosures**

You acknowledge that we may use third-party advertising companies (as mentioned in the Third Parties” section above) to deliver information to you and that they have the ability to utilize tracking technologies for their own use. You may want to opt out or select a “Do Not Track” setting. “Do Not Track” is a privacy setting you can typically set in your browser. Please keep in mind that the settings you select are specific to the browser on a particular device and that if you use a different browser, you will need to opt-out again. If you would like to learn more, including how to turn on “Do Not Track,” visit [donottrack.us](http://donottrack.us/). Inside Weddings uses Google Analytics, which uses cookies and other, similar technologies to collect information about use of the Site anonymously and report trends, without identifying individual users, therefore our Site does not respond to browser-based “Do Not Track” signals. To opt out of the use of Google Analytics, visit <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

**How We May Use Your Information**

As mentioned above, Inside Weddings and our third-party providers may use your information for a variety of purposes. Some ways in which we may use your information: (1) enabling Members to use the Site and the Site’s features and services; (2) responding to Members requests, questions, and concerns; (3) processing and fulfilling Business Members’ transactions; protecting our copyrights and property; and (4) personalizing your user experience on the Site (tailored to your interests based on history with us, such as images you “Favorite”).

To perform these functions, we may match information collected from you through different means or at different times, along with information obtained from other sources, such as third parties. This information may be used to analyze your specific interests on the Site or be used in the aggregated analytics. 

**How We May Share Information with Others**

We may share the information – both Personal Information and non-personally identifying information – we collect on the Site with our partners, affiliates, or third-party providers for various reasons. For example: (1) We may aggregate information for marketing and/or promotional purposes. Though we try to match items or services carefully with your interests, you may elect to opt out, as mentioned in the Opt In/Opt Out section; (2) For Members wanting to subscribe to our publication(s) or Business Members paying for Premium Listings, some of your information may be collected by third-party providers on our behalf, such as payment processing address verification, and credit pre-authorization, or even to personalize content (e.g. suggesting an article or inspiration board); (3) For contest, sweepstakes, and the like, we may share your information with our co-sponsor(s) – unless you chose to opt out; (4) Legal investigation purposes or to follow the law; and (5) For any change within the corporation or a wind-down of business.

Additionally, you acknowledge that if you choose to participate in public areas of our Site, such as Reviews, the information you voluntarily disclose will be accessible to other Site Members and, in some cases, the general public. You are responsible for any content that you post and you should be cautious about the information you submit to these areas.

**Member-Uploaded Information  **

Inspiration boards, images, Reviews, and other Member-uploaded information to the Site, is deemed public and may be available for other Inside Weddings Members access or viewing, provided that the Member uploading the Content does not choose to mark the content as private. Private inspiration boards are visible to you and other participants on the board, and any participant may choose to make the contents of the board available to anyone else. For example, another participant may invite someone else to the board, or even just take an image from the board and email it to their friends. You post content on the Site at your own risk. Although we allow you to set privacy options, please be aware that no security measures are guaranteed, and we cannot control the actions of other Site Members with whom you may choose to share your information. Therefore, we cannot and do not guarantee that content you post on the Site will not be viewed by unauthorized persons. 

We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on the Site. You understand and acknowledge that, even after removal, copies of content you post may remain viewable in cached and archived pages on the internet or if other Site Members have copied or stored content you post. Any improper collection or misuse of information provided on Inside Weddings is a violation of our Terms of Use and should be reported via [security@insideweddings.com](mailto:security@insideweddings.com).

**Mobile Applications**

Inside Weddings may make mobile applications (“apps”) available for you to download and use on your mobile device or smartphone and/or tablet. Similar to the information we collect when you use a computer, we may also collect Personal Information as well as other usage information through the app. Some information, for example, such as real-time location may be able to be modified by managing your location preferences in the app and/or device directly. This Policy may be supplemented with additional terms or privacy policies of which we will notify you by posting them on such apps.

**CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS**

California's "Shine the Light" law, Civil Code section 1798.83, requires certain businesses to respond to requests from California customers asking about the businesses' practices related to disclosing Personal Information to third parties for the third parties' direct marketing purposes. Alternately, such businesses may have in place a policy not to disclose Personal Information of customers to third parties for the third parties' direct marketing purposes if the customer has exercised an option to opt out of such information-sharing. As discussed above, if you wish to opt out of our sharing of your information with third parties for the third parties' direct marketing purposes, edit your preferences in your account profile at [www.insideweddings.com](http://www.insideweddings.com/), or email us at [membersupport@insideweddings.com](mailto:membersupport@insideweddings.com) (please include your name, mailing address, and email address). To find out more about your opt-out rights, see the "Opt In and Opt Out Section" section above.

**SECURITY**

We take great effort to safeguard the Personal Information collected on this Site. If we believe that the security of your Personal Information in our care may have been compromised, you acknowledge that we may seek to notify you by email. Although we cannot guarantee the security of the information collected and received, we have implemented safeguards intended to eliminate the risk of a security breach. 

For example, where appropriate, we: 

  * store data in controlled facilities;
  * Secure Sockets Layer (SSL); 
  * use HTTPS encryption when you authenticate (i.e., log into one of our Services), which helps prevent unauthorized access to your login credentials;
  * restrict certain employees from accessing Personal Information who do not need that access to perform their jobs
  * require our employees to use password-protected screen savers when leaving their desks;

**TRANSFER OF INFORMATION**

If you are located outside of the United States, you should know that the information you provide to us is being transmitted to us and processed in the United States and will be protected subject to this Policy and United States laws, which may differ from the laws in your country. Please be advised that we may transfer your information to and from any state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction, and process it in the United States or elsewhere. Your consent to this Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to any such transfer. 

**POLICY FOR MINORS**

The Site is intended for adults over 18 years of age. The Site is not intended for minors under 13 years of age. If you do not satisfy this age requirement, you are not permitted to use or enter the Site. We do not knowingly collect or store any personally identifiable information from minors under the age of 13. If you are under 13, please do not register on the Site or send us any information about yourself. If you believe that we might have any information from a minor under the age of 13, please contact us at [security@insideweddings.com](mailto:security@insideweddings.com). If we become aware that a minor under 13 has provided us with personal information, we will take the necessary steps to remove such information and terminate the minor’s account.

**CHANGES TO THIS POLICY**

We reserve the right to change this Policy at any time, without actual notice to you. You can determine when the Policy was last revised by referring to the “Last Updated” date at the top left of this page. You should periodically check this page to ensure you are familiar with any changes. You understand and agree that your continued access to or use of the Site after the effective date of modifications to the Policy indicates your acceptance of the changes.

**CONTACT US  
** If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Policy or about our privacy practices in general, please email [membersupport@insideweddings.com](mailto:membersupport@insideweddings.com) and write "Privacy Policy" in the subject line. You may also write to Inside Weddings Member Services at 6255 W. Sunset Blvd., Suite 860, Los Angeles, CA 90028 or call (323) 373-3360.
